FANSUB GROUP AZALIA PRESENTS
Worked on the series:
Lily, Tiramisu, Biryulka, Host, Zinger
How did I become
queen
All characters are fictitious
and the events shown are fiction.
-Your Majesty!
It's a real miracle for us
that after every day there comes tomorrow.
It's dangerous. There may be another explosion.
Your Majesty!
No. You can't go there.
-Your Majesty!
-Protect the king.
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty, we need to leave.
-Your Majesty!
-Hurry up.
No. We need to save him!
-Your Majesty.
-Don't go there.
Don't interfere.
What are you saying? King...
Listen to me!
I'll explain everything to you later.
Now save yourself.
-Your Majesty!
-It's dangerous here
take the queen to Daejojeon.
-Your Majesty, don't go there.
-Your Majesty.
-Let me in!
Let me in, please.
Let me go!
Let me in!
Your Majesty!
However
we don't understand how wonderful it is,
until the day comes that has no tomorrow.
We are so stupid that we don’t value something
until we lose it.
Tomorrow never comes
Episode 13
Someone dared to make an attempt on the king's life in the palace.
Catch all suspicious persons and interrogate them.
We have to find out
who is behind this?
Have you prepared this?
How are you going to deal with the consequences after planning something like this?
Calm down.
As if I could calm down!
The king's life was threatened in front of everyone,
and so on display.
So, everything has been decided
that I made an attempt on his life?
I'll take care of it.
I beg you. I pray.
I desperately pray to the gods of heaven and earth.
Save our king.
I beg you. I pray.
I beg you.
Save
our king.
I didn't know they would go this far.
They themselves placed him on the throne,
and now they want to get rid of him.
What happens if the king doesn't wake up?
Then the royal concubine and I will be powerless.
I can't believe we got it right
into a trap set for the queen.
I beg you. I pray.
I beg you.
Get some rest.
You will fall so soon.
If the king doesn't survive,
I won't be able to live either.
If you have to die,
Before death I will take revenge on the king’s offender.
Palace
and those people
made us angry.
Your Majesty. The head of the Detective Department came.
And Cheoljong...
Is the king okay?
Prince Yeonpyeong prohibited
enter Hijeongjon while the king is being treated.
And nothing is said about the king's condition.
I have to go to him.
Don't go.
They'll let me in.
I'm still his wife.
Don't go.
He made an attempt on your life.
You have every right to kill him.
Soyeon.
I need to rest.
Are you sure there won't be any problems?
Certainly.
Who was behind this?
We are innocent.
We are ready to give our lives to protect the king.
We are the royal guard.
Why do you need fake documents?
You used this excuse to detain us,
and at this time the king suffered.
Behind this is the one
who found errors in our documents. Your father
Kim Jwageun!
This is Kim Jwageun.
You're pretty smart.
I have everything figured out.
As you thought, the incense burner was not filled with sand,
and gunpowder used as explosives.
How did you guess?
How did it go?
It is not easy to force them to confess.
Without a doubt.
Did you find out anything else?
Not yet.
We need to find the criminals to put an end to this.
Find the instigator as soon as possible.
Yes.
Find out where the gunpowder comes from.
Move quietly and alone.
Yes.
Mister.
Please forgive me.
What are you doing? Too many eyes.
I beg you.
Listen to me.
It won't take much time. Just a little.
Please. Not for long.
I'm just in case
kept the ledger.
I never even thought of using it.
Besides, the queen knew nothing about it.
Where is the ledger now?
Isn't she in your possession?
Then she can only be
at the king's.
How so.
The traces you left have put our clan in danger.
This is enough to punish you.
I'll do whatever you say.
If you tell me to die, I will die.
Right here.
I'll hang myself right here.
I'm hanging myself.
Spare me, sir.
Spare me.
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, have you come to your senses?
My brother.
Yes. Continue.
Why is it so noisy here?
It's so noisy it gives me a headache.
I can't hear anything.
Turn down the noise.
I had to explain.
I should have told him that the king did not try to kill me.
He made an attempt on your life.
You have every right to kill him.
You will have to pay for your recklessness.
Is the Kim clan behind this?
Or another clan?
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty. The king came to his senses.
He seems to have woken up.
He just fell asleep.
Why did you wrap him up like that?
Looks too sick.
Unfortunately,
The explosion caused him to lose his hearing.
Just don't say
that he would be deaf for the rest of his life.
Only time will tell.
Leave us alone.
Yes.
Will you say again that this is not the work of your family?
You told me
that I will lose someone dear to my heart.
Now in my heart
there is no one left.
That's why I ask
stop it.
Your Majesty, stop worrying.
Who...
My king, are you awake?
Let me wet your lips.
Queen's Dictionary
So you went to visit the king.
I came to console you after what happened
and ask a few questions.
Your father has lost an important thing.
I'm sure the king took her secretly.
Do you know anything about this?
- I got it, I’m going for help.
-No.
No one should know that I...
What am I...
So you know something.
Remember how I said
that our kind has no weaknesses?
Because we immediately get rid of them.
Let me ask you one last time.
Is there anything you want to tell me?
When we were in my house
I saved the king when he fell into the well.
Maybe it was then...
Some time ago I made you an offer.
The day you fell into the lake.
Let me remind you.
I asked you to keep an eye on your husband.
you will accept
my suggestion?
And what will I get in return?
What do you want?
Guarantees of my safety.
Your Highness, it's time for you to return.
Queen's Dictionary
I shouldn't have gotten here
Jang Bong-hwan
Cheoljong.
Sorry.
You'll still lose.
I'm on the winning side.
Kim Soyeon, you still said goodbye to life.
Since I already had the chance to take your place,
let me live this life well.
In order for this to succeed, I need to find out
what happened that day.
Someday you too will lose
person dear to you.
You must love me.
Is this an order?
There is nothing real about me, everything is a lie.
You are Soyeon.
Have you taken this position yourself?
If you want to die, die in the palace.
Tomorrow you will become queen.
From now on
tell me everything about him.
Ask me
keep an eye on the king?
Don't follow the king
and not take your eyes off your husband.
Don't want.
Don't you want queen status
and the king?
You must do what you were born to do.
How they did it in the past.
When they told me that the king was in the well.
If you don't do your part,
the king is useless. From useless
need to get rid of it.
If you harm the king,
I won't stand by.
So what will you do?
You are very mistaken.
Do you think the queen has power?
The queen is only needed for
production of heirs.
If you become queen
What kind of power do you think you will have?
like a simple woman?
This is not just because of Kim Jwageun's words.
Even after staying in the palace for a short time,
I've experienced enough to realize reality.
The whole palace
killed Kim Seo-yeon.
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, Your Majesty!
Queen, what are you doing here so late?
Why are you soaked through?
Did they really fall into the lake again?
Why do you keep doing this?
Now you must gather your strength.
Otherwise, why have I tried so hard until now?
Why did I have to go through such humiliation?
Why do you need this?
For your own profit
to fill your storehouses.
You sold your daughter out of greed.
-Soyeon.
-Why did you always ask me?
become a queen, the pride of the family?
Why did they say that once I became queen, I could do whatever I wanted?
Why should I, suffering from guilt for the death of my mother,
did you inspire your dreams?
Do you even know what I was thinking when I jumped into the lake?
The life I thought was mine was a lie.
Even the dreams were not mine.
I'm a complete failure.
That's why I ran away.
What?
On the day your dream came true,
I lost the most dear person.
Myself.
It was you who pushed me into this lake.
It is convenient for children to blame their parents for everything.
There was no need to blame my father.
Your Majesty.
I have to say something.
I know that you will do anything for me.
That is, I found out.
My memories have returned.
Don't do anything else.
If you're worried about me, don't do anything.
This is the only thing that will help me.
Soyeon.
Don't call me by name.
I just
the queen, whom the Detective Department serves.
Queen's Dictionary
arrow, lotto, special forces, kitchen police, ramen
Social distancing
means every man for himself.
showdown, jasmine tea, bad manners.
I'll tell the truth since you can't hear me.
I decided to live a long life.
I will betray you.
I choose the path that will save my life.
And don't die.
Recover as if nothing happened.
And then I can stab you in the back.
You were right.
The king was stronger than he showed.
I regret this.
What do you think about today's case?
We found gunpowder at the explosion site.
-Powder?
-Yes.
There are two types of gunpowder in Joseon.
The one delivered from the Qing Empire.
And a local one from the gunpowder warehouse.
They have a slight difference in structure.
The one we found is local.
The powder magazine is part of the weapons room.
And the armory room is in charge of the Minister of War.
He is my father's right hand.
This means...
My father was the one who brought the king to the throne.
The king showed his true colors
his father wants to eliminate him,
until it became his mistake,
and field guards with fake
individuals responsible for the explosion.
This must be his plan.
When was the last time you came to me,
you wanted something.
So what do you want?
I want
king.
I can't stop now.
And if that's how you feel, Soyeon,
this is another reason.
I came here to tell you about
what did the queen do yesterday?
She saved the feast
which was bound to fail.
Do you think I'll believe you?
You probably think
It was I who caused the incident with the king.
If you check, you will easily find the answer.
As I understand it, you wanted to ruin the feast.
Even if the queen is stripped of her title...
I don't need any titles.
I just want the queen
disappeared from the king's sight.
This means
that the king likes the queen.
By the looks of it, you had a hard time.
Are you that worried about the king?
God.
He only recently became your son-in-law.
You seem to have become attached to him.
Well,
to be honest,
I did something
which will dishonor our family.
I kept records illegally
acquired property of our family.
And I lost them.
What?
I found out where the book is now.
I just need to find her and get rid of her.
But I ask you to spare the queen.
Why did you suddenly mention her?
The man who now has the book
this is the king.
The Queen has no
attitude towards this situation.
The king misled her and me.
Yes, he misled everyone.
I will accept any punishment you give me.
But
Have mercy Soyeon.
Spare the queen.
I beg you, have mercy on the queen.
Father.
Did you sleep in the Detective Department?
Yes. This is a big deal, I have a lot of work to do.
Everything in the case indicates
at me as if I were a criminal.
But you didn't talk about it.
Don't worry.
The detective department took up the investigation.
If you have been slandered,
I will reveal the real culprit of this incident.
It's calming.
Recently
you said you made up your mind
on the scale of your dreams.
So how big is your dream?
My dream is
become at least half as successful as you are.
It's already late. Rest.
Don't come near.
If you follow me, I will kill myself.
Soyeon.
I know what motivates you.
So where is the queen early in the morning?
She's in the royal kitchen.
Now.
Nothing.
I wanted her to cook
I'll have breakfast when he wakes up.
And she’s already cooking for her grandma, that’s how it is.
That scared me.
It's early after all. What are you cooking?
I've been so depressed lately.
And I can’t sleep.
It's like I'm saying my morning prayer,
I make a very annoying dish,
which needs to be crushed
and stir a million times.
But the rice porridge looks a little strange.
This is not rice porridge. This is potage.
Are you tongue-tied? It's still early.
It means "carrot porridge."
Wait a minute, I need to write this down.
And how to do it?
You need to chop the onions and carrots
and cook for an hour in water.
Then grind in a mortar.
It's like you're crushing everything
experiences and illusions.
Then stir over low heat
so that it does not burn and there are no clots.
With a sense of self-improvement.
Season with salt
and add a little milk.
Even milk?
That's all?
No.
You need to prepare vegetable soup in advance.
Take the broth
and add a little to the porridge
for a rich taste.
You need to be so confused
just to add a little?
I told you so. It's like morning prayer.
You put your heart and soul into it.
I'm sure the king will come to his senses right away,
as soon as he tries.
This is not for him.
What to suffer twice, I’ll figure it out in one fell swoop.
Because I said something to her last time
makes me eat with my mother-in-law?
She dared her wayward
say with my mouth that I'm old,
Should I look at her first thing in the morning?
What is this?
This is brunch.
Brunch?
Means "women meet together."
This is the time when women gather for breakfast
and get closer to each other.
Everyone knows what it is.
It's like you're not from Gojoseon.
Asshole.
I used to do this often at home.
It was a long time ago.
Asshole.
This is carrot porridge.
It contains many products that
will help improve vision.
Yes?
Queen Mother, eat more.
It seems like you've become blind lately.
If that’s the case, then I think the queen should eat everything.
What the? Why are they so cocky?
Very tasty.
Edible.
From now on
I will make sure that
we got together more often.
-Scoundrel.
-What a bastard.
Then I apologize.
I'll bring you some drinks.
Rumors about culinary skills
queens are a bit exaggerated.
The ability to recognize good food -
this is a component of nobility.
You're letting the queen get away with everything
just for this talent?
Since it was you who conveyed to me the queen's words,
I can't believe it.
Of course you won't believe what I say.
I heard the king and queen
They secretly exchanged notes all night.
I wonder what they wrote to each other?
I'll bring your drinks.
It is a drink made from wine and various fruits,
boiled with anise and cinnamon.
Wine first thing in the morning?
All the alcohol has evaporated
the only products left are those
help maintain youth.
It's more of a medicine than a drink.
I can't believe you thought of making wine.
How did you come up with this idea?
Where do you get inspiration for your dishes?
I don't know what to call it
inspiration or creation.
When I see the ingredients, I immediately think:
how to preserve their original taste.
During these times, they were wary of the West,
so I won’t say that this is French cuisine.
Madam.
Hello sir.
I've been waiting to talk to you.
What? What do you want to talk about?
After the incident with the king
I was overcome by different thoughts.
Nobody knows what will happen next
and tomorrow may be the last.
If my life ends tomorrow,
What will I regret most?
About feelings that I couldn't express
because I doubted it.
One sincere word
better than any sophisticated confession.
Therefore
I want to tell you
that I love you.
I don't like you.
What?
About gunpowder.
Amount of gunpowder produced in the south
Gyeongsangdo Province,
and the quantity arriving at the warehouse vary.
I knew it.
Is the king still unconscious?
Yes.
I heard he lost his hearing. This will be a problem in the future.
About this incident with the king.
For an explosion of this magnitude
did you use gunpowder?
I'm not sure.
It could be sulfur or explosive gas.
If it were sulfur, there would be a smell,
so the king would have noticed him.
If it were gas it would be difficult
prevent it from leaking and explode all at once.
The culprits are interrogated, but they do not confess.
It's difficult to know who is behind this.
When I see the ingredients, I immediately think:
how to preserve their original taste.
Can't be.
Guilty of treason
have the leader been revealed?
Looks like low ranking guards
opposing the Royal Court,
got together and caused an explosion.
Is it true?
You say no one is behind them?
In something as big as the murder of a king?
This is impossible.
The ones we have to fear most are those who have nothing to lose.
They probably thought
that they can't rise higher,
so we decided to radically change the situation.
This is probably the reason.
It makes sense. Act of treason for the purpose of enthronement
the king's half-brother, Lee Wong-gyeong,
also committed by low-ranking guards.
Considering that the king is unconscious,
The longer we delay this, the more confusion there will be.
Therefore
the seven culprits will take full responsibility
and will be sentenced to death.
For attempting to assassinate the king
and conspiracy to commit treason
you are sentenced to death.
Do you have the last word?
If you sentence them to death,
you will never know who was behind all this.
They said that no one was behind this.
This is a rash decision...
This decision was made after a night of investigation.
Beheaded.
Stop.
The investigation was carried out
by royal order.
Are you going to interrupt us?
Release the innocent immediately.
This is a real order.
Sorry I'm late.
You...
I heard you were unconscious.
I'm young and full of strength
so I recovered quickly.
I didn't want to lie in vain
and recover in bed.
So I looked for those
who plotted to kill me.
First I found out about you.
Are you saying you checked us?
Someone is plotting treason.
Say that your personal life is more important
what is the life of a king?
No, that's not true.
If you have nothing to hide, then there is nothing to be afraid of.
Don't worry.
I found the leader.
-What is he talking about?
-What's happening?
In the bakhurnitsa used in the ceremony,
Gunpowder was found in large quantities.
-Powder?
Large quantity?
Bahurnitsa will become a huge bomb.
-It's too dangerous.
-Everything has already been decided.
Tracing the origins of gunpowder,
I received information
what is this gunpowder
trade unofficially at the port of Tonne.
By the way, why do you need so much gunpowder?
To attack Joseon again a little later.
Thank you.
-Thank you?
-Thank you.
Thank you.
Where did this gunpowder come from?
It is produced only for military purposes.
It cannot in any way be produced for personal use,
After all, this is a dangerous and valuable commodity.
So, I looked at all the places where gunpowder is made in Joseon.
And I discovered something strange.
In certain areas at production sites
They constantly pocketed some amount of gunpowder.
The amount of concealed gunpowder
It was small at first, but grew over time.
Straight
how greed grows.
-What?
-This is true?
Do you know when the gunpowder theft began?
troop commander Kim Jwageun?
In the same year that I ascended the throne.
In the same year, Mr. Kim Jwageun became the commander of the troops.
Your Majesty, this is a false accusation.
Be silent!
The Minister of War, responsible for the production of gunpowder,
also a traitor who plotted treason with Kim Jwageun!
I'm using the royal guard's fake identities as bait.
Kim Jwageun should have found out about this by now.
You will go through unbearable torture,
but bear with them.
I will definitely save you.
This is a false accusation
understand this, Your Majesty!
If you say again that you are being falsely accused,
I will immediately give you poison to drink.
Gunpowder merchants sold it
anyone who paid.
Bandits, even the Japanese!
If this is not for the sake of destroying Joseon, then for what?
Who else was here with them?
Troop commander Kim Jwageun.
Minister of War Kim Chang-hyuk.
These two
stole national weapons to weaken the army,
and planned an assassination attempt on me, the king,
which means they are guilty of treason.
What should we call this operation?
Phoenix.
Operation name -
burning phoenix.
For all the crimes
those responsible will be dismissed from office
and exiled.
Your Majesty.
-The Dowager Queen.
What are you doing?
Why do you judge without reason?
You must have lost your mind after the explosion.
Remember the boundaries of what is permitted!
Is that so?
If you say so
You must have lost your mind due to old age.
I cannot continue discussing political issues while you are in this state.
Please leave your regency.
-What?
-What is he talking about?
It's time for me to make my own decisions.
Your Majesty!
I should have given Kim Jwageun the poison to drink immediately
and execute his entire family.
But because of you and the queen
I decided to just strip him of his title.
Don't you like it?
Are you trying to make a deal with me in exchange for my brother's life?
You can only call it a deal if you have a choice.
Your Majesty.
I, Kim Jwageun, have been falsely accused
but I will prove my loyalty,
obeying the royal order.
What a relief.
I was afraid that because you are old, you might be consumed by greed.
I'm not against being removed from office.
But I ask you to give me the opportunity
clear your name.
I ask Sakhonbu to be removed from his position.
I accept your request.
But if Sakhonbu does not remove him from office by tomorrow,
I will immediately remove the commander of the troops, Kim Jwageun, from his position.
and I will dissolve not only Sakhonbu himself,
but also all the officials present!
-We ask for your mercy!
You have lost.
You were kicked out by the king to whom you yourself gave the throne!
I didn't know that the king would plan his own assassination attempt.
Who do you think set the trap?
I entrusted you with the selection of noblewomen.
But you don't understand people well.
Confucius said that the heart is more complex than nature,
and seeing someone else's heart is more difficult than seeing what is behind the clouds.
I made a mistake in the selection of noblewomen
both in the palace and outside it.
You also trusted the queen
take care of the selection of royal concubines.
But she made a choice in favor of the king.
And it was the queen who saved the feast,
that I ruined it.
The enemy is terrible when he is among his own.
Your Highness.
His Majesty must have regained consciousness.
I can keep an eye on my husband
when he regains consciousness.
If he doesn't wake up, I'll be useless.
If I become useless, I will be overthrown.
If I'm overthrown, I'll give up thoughts of revenge
and open a restaurant to earn a living.
Not too bad.
Queen!
His Majesty...
He regained consciousness.
Is it true?
Yes. His hearing has returned
and he went to the royal council.
I was really scared.
I have to go.
-Your Majesty!
I don't have time.
I'm so glad.
I'm really very happy.
Don't cry. Why are you crying?
It's such a relief.
Court lady Choi.
-I'll do it.
-Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty.
Everything is fine now.
Everything is fine because you are awake and healthy.
I will never lose you again.
Hwajin.
Queen's Dictionary
Your Majesty.
They said that you would visit the king. Why are you sitting here?
Another glass.
It’s somehow awkward to see him sober.
Stop drinking. You shouldn't do this, Your Majesty.
You've had enough work. Go home!
I'll drink this to you.
Court lady Choi.
There is an unlimited supply of alcohol in the royal kitchen.
Why are you embarrassed?
It's awkward because...
You're right. Why is this awkward?
I'm confident in myself! Let's go to the king.
You can't go now
go when you sober up.
Fine. Let's go tomorrow.
Let's put this off until tomorrow.
Just like going on a diet.
We have tomorrow!
Royal chef. Another bottle.
Does she think she came to the tavern or what?
Faster.
Court lady Kan.
Secret
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty.
This was found in the Daejojeon Hall.
As expected, the king and queen work together.
The Queen is completely broken.
Broken things need to be replaced with new ones.
But you can make a broken thing last until the end
and send it to the fire.
Maybe we use real arsenic?
The Queen loves to eat so much.
So let's set the table for her.
Are you going to leave the king?
We have to break it
to continue to use it.
If this happens as soon as he
will give his heart to the queen, he will understand
that everyone on his side will become unhappy.
Isn't it a miracle
that tomorrow comes every day?
Let's go to the second round in the Songjeongjong Hall.
The king's recovery must be celebrated.
Please don't shout, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty!
You can't call him that.
Open.
Potatoes "Spiral"
Are you sleeping?
I think I fell asleep.
Have you been looking out for me?
Why do you always do this?
You worry about me, you try to understand me.
Come to think of it, you were the first person I saw when I came here.
I owe you so much.
I thought about you when I tried to leave the palace.
Thought I'd never see you again.
Hong Young.
Are you awake?
I am sure that the soul of this woman has taken possession of my body.
Why do you always avoid me?
-Wait.
-What did he want to ask me?
Did you like it?
Didn't she say that this is prohibited?
She said that hugging, smiling and lying next to you -
all this is prohibited.
I forbid you to say that this is prohibited.
I've prepared everything.
What do you see?
Someone will die in the palace today.
I can't believe they tried to get rid of the queen.
I specially prepared ice, which today is more valuable than gold.
-Your Majesty.
-My queen.